five organs in our body that we cannot control.
The first is the brain. The second is
our heart. The third is our lungs. The fourth is
our kidneys. The
fifth is our liver. If any of these organs
suffer from any illness, our
financial situation will be very limited. Not only will
our health go to a very bad
stage, but
our financial situation will also go to a very bad
stage. All of these are
considered critical illnesses. Apart from this, critical illnesses
like cancer can also occur. Similarly,
major accidents can
happen. We take health insurance to help us when such major
accidents and difficulties
come into our lives
or to prevent
us from being financially exhausted.
Of course, everyone should keep this in mind when
taking health insurance. If
we have any such illness and need hospital expenses, we should be able to get
health insurance without fear, without fear, without tension, and if we
have health insurance, we should be able to get that treatment and get back to
life.  The
most basic need of insurance is that
our hospital expenses
will be covered by this health insurance.  But
after such illnesses or major accidents, it may not be possible for us to
return to our old lives,
or we
may have to set aside a long period of time for that.  Even with
illnesses like cancer,
sometimes we can't
return to our old jobs or lives
.  Even
after we return home from treatment,
we will be financially devastated.
We will have a label across the country that says "home for people with cancer."  It may be a
pitiful
look towards us.   This is
an issue where even small amounts of money given by visitors who come to see us naturally can become a significant amount of money for us.
So, in such a situation, I am
introducing you to
a plan that can be taken at a small premium in order to get an amount in our account if something like this happens in our life. Today, I am introducing you to a plan in
that category called Critical Illness Policies.
Today, I am
introducing to you a
plan called Critical Shield by ICICI Lampard. There are so many
insurance companies in India that are still coming up with
new ones. Even if you ask me
why
I am suggesting this Critical Shield by ICC Lampard, there are
three reasons for that. The
first reason is that in the Critical Shield
plan, the survival period is zero and it is
said that you can take a policy. Now, suppose a person gets a critical
illness and dies with that critical illness.
How much money will the company give
you? Give the
amount that the customer said they would give to that
person's family.
Meanwhile, the survival period is one.  In
policies that have a 15-day or 7-day, 3-day, or 15-day period, those who
die will not get it. If they
go to the hospital and survive, the amount will be based on how many
days they survive. If
seven days are
mentioned in the criticality policy, if
a person has a heart
attack and goes to the hospital for
treatment and dies on the
eighth day of his life, the
amount will be
received only if the person dies. In this plan, even if the
person
dies with that illness, this amount will be received. Cancer
or stroke or
any problems in the legs, kidney failure,
whatever, if this illness is identified and immediately
dies, you will
get coverage within it. This is one
reason why I selected this because other plans in the market do not offer it. The
second reason is that in
this policy, we usually have a
criticality policy that covers everything once and
its purpose is to
Okay, why did you take that policy? The
intention of that policyholder is
complete. So let's say a person
took a policy and the first thing that happened to him was a
stroke. He claimed
this amount for that stroke, the
criticality amount, and it was full.
So after a few days,
he had a heart
attack. If he had a heart attack, he wouldn't get any benefit from it
because the policy had expired. The policy
he had got along with the stroke
expired. He
couldn't continue. Because of this stroke,
naturally, he couldn't
go and take a policy later.
So it became a
dead end there. Meanwhile, in
this plan, we don't have that. We have
five
categories of criticality. We
can claim each time within these five categories. For example, a person had a heart
attack and he had a heart
attack and he survived.
He has this zero survival.  It does
n't matter because it is a period.
He got that amount and then
he continued that policy.
After some time, he got a
stroke.
Then he got cancer and he
still got the same amount. If we say that this policy will continue like this, then
we will say that there is an incident in our life and
this policy will not end there
or if
criticality comes and the purpose
is not complete. The purpose is that if we get the
next criticality, we can continue it as much as we
can.
Life long
Namukt can be renewed.
Only if a person gets five types of criticality, the purpose of this
policy is complete.
Until then, we
can continue it. This is also the
second reason why I choose this. The third reason is that it
covers more than 126 critical illnesses and surgeries as well. It
provides such extensive coverage.  When
I
looked at it, I could see that there was no other plan available in the market.
What is important in it?
Now, let's
give you an example. If we have
a
policy that only says that it will cover liver cirrhosis if we get liver cirrhosis, but if it says that it will not cover liver fibrosis, then the
company will deny it by saying that it cannot be given. Even though we
have taken a critical illness policy, when we get a critical
illness, it did
not cover it. Now, when we get
a rare disease like myelofibrosis, it comes
naturally to us, and even there, the company
says that if it is a policy that does not cover things like myelofibrosis or
aplastic anemia, it does not
cover anything like this.
Sometimes, when you hear these names, those who have not heard them
may be surprised, but there are many types of critical
illnesses. Many types. When I started
working in health insurance for a few years, I became
serious.  When it
comes down to it, thousands of people are
suffering from these kinds of critical illnesses.
One reason I say this is because of plastic
anemia.  Plastic anemia is
a critical illness.   They will not
provide health insurance to those who come.  So,
we need to understand what types of illnesses we are likely to encounter in our lives.   The
main reason for this is our
current lifestyle and pollution
.  We
can't change it.
Can we go and live in the forest with that in mind?   No,
that's not it.  So,
naturally, we will just
accept all of this and go away.  But
we need protection for that.
What is protection for?
Protection for our financial security.
Why do we look at financial security?  If
we survive after all this,
we should be
able to live happily ever after.   Don't
go into poverty.  If not,
we will have this situation where we are the
breadwinners or the family is financially dependent on the
income that one person gets from going to work. If
something like this happens to that person,
then that family or
their children's upbringing will go into
a
state of complete chaos. It will destroy the
future of the family, including those children. So, it is
said that a policy like this should be taken to prevent such situations from happening.  So, let's take a closer
look at the ICICI Bank's Critical Shield plan that I mentioned.
There are many things within this that we need to learn and understand.
My advice to you is that
before you take out any financial transaction, be it health insurance or any other, do so
only after you are fully aware of what you are doing
.  Under someone's influence, instead of taking what
someone we know comes and says,
why am I taking it? So
you should have a clear idea of ​​what I will get. There is an old saying that says, "Even if you throw it in the attic, you should measure it." That is, even if you throw it in the
river, you should measure it. That is, when
we
spend money, if it is financial,
where does it go before it leaves our hands? So,
you should have a clear idea of ​​what I will get. So, whether it is
health insurance or
this criticality policy,
you should understand it in detail before taking it.
This video of mine is just a small
introduction. Never
think that this is an expert advice and do not make a decision based on this single video. If
you have any doubts, you can
call me directly on the number I have given here. I will give you the full details of this and
convince you. After giving you
accurate information about what is inside it, how it is, and how it is,
We will only go forward
.  The new name for Critty Shield is now
Critty Shield Plus,
previously it was
just Critty Shield
.  It has brought a few updates this year
.  I
meant to do this earlier, but I put it off for
a while because there were updates coming
.  So,
based on the updates, I decided to make a
video detailing it
.  There are four main
types of plans.  One is
Cancer Shield, the second is Cardiac
Shield, the third is Cancer and
Cardiac combined and
called Cancer Plus Cardiac Shield, and the fourth is Comprehensive
Critical Shield.  The only plan I recommend to
everyone is the
Comprehensive Critical Shield
.
You can choose the rest according to your preference
This is not a subject we would ever force anyone into.   So, within this,
I recommend the Comprehensive Critical Shield
.  Now let's take a look at what's inside this cancer
shield, cardiac shield, and then
move forward.  If this
cancer is a shield, we would
have four major cancers and one minor cancer within it.  When we
say major cancer, all
types of major cancers are covered
.  Bone marrow transplantation,
aplastic anemia, and primary
myelofibrosis are some of the major issues
covered.  Similarly, the early
stages of cancer, regardless of the cancer, are also
covered within this
.  There will be an initial waiting
period of 90 days.   As
we said earlier, there is a zero survival
period.  The second one is the
cardiac shield.  It is
said that in Kerala, more people die from heart attacks than from accidents.
One of the important reasons for this is that
statistics show that one in four people in Kerala is diagnosed with diabetes.
So, an immediate result of this diabetes is
cardiac arrest. The
second problem is stroke. The
third problem is kidney failure. The
fourth problem is
increased creatinine levels and many other
problems that can be related to it. That is why this
diabetes is
called the deadliest disease and the silent killer. Out of these,
10 major illnesses and 11 minor critical
illnesses are covered. Those who
call me can
give me a detailed list.
Within this, 90 days is the waiting period. If it is said that the
person who takes the policy first has a
heart attack
or cancer or
whatever illness that comes after 90 days, it will
not matter if it comes and he dies from it, but only after the first 90 days.
Now, if
we want, we can
add PD and take it.
There is an option to add the personal accident that I mentioned in detail. Similarly, there is an
option to add major surgeries.
Now, the third option, as we
said earlier, is a mix of both cardiac plus cancer.
It
covers 14 major illnesses and 12 binary illnesses.
Now, the option that I suggest is the
option called Comprehensive Critical Shield Plus. It covers 55 major
illnesses and 37 minor illnesses.
Similarly, we
can optionally add the restoration benefit of cancer. Once we
get cancer, we have applied for it.
Now, we have taken Rs. 10 lakhs for which we
got Rs. 10 lakhs.  If
cancer comes back, you'll get this ten lakh rupees again
.  That's what's called the Cancer Restoration
Benefit.  Similarly,
we
can add 107 surgical procedures within this, including major surgical procedures.  No, sorry, 107 surgical
procedures, we can add them in here
.  This includes 58
minor surgeries and 48 major
surgeries,
as well as surgeries that are not considered critical
.
Anyone who wants a detailed list of what it is can
contact me at the number provided here
.  If you want to take out this critical illness policy, no
one who is currently ill can do it.
Those who currently have diseases such as sugar, cholesterol, BP, etc.
cannot take out this criticality policy.  So, no matter
how old you are,
these issues don't matter
.  If you have no other major health problems,
take out this policy immediately.   If
we suddenly get these kinds of illnesses and then
want to take them, it won't work.
So
you should take out a policy while you are healthy.
That's why it's said that if you save money during times of prosperity, you'll eat
money during times of adversity.
If you do something like this while you're healthy now,
it will be useful when you get sick.  Now, if you start getting sick and start experiencing
symptoms, and then you
go and get it,
sometimes you don't even get it.
Sometimes,
even if you take out health insurance, this is what we're
talking about now, critical illness plans
.
Even if we take out normal health insurance, we may sometimes encounter
a situation where we do not get health insurance
.  So, if
you are in good health right now, I would
say you should go and get a policy right now.  That's
my advice. Now we
can add PA inside.
What is a personal accident policy?
Many people are confused about what a personal accident policy is.
I'll make
a video explaining it in detail.
But let me tell you something briefly here
.  If you are the owner of your home and
your income is going to be used to pay for a
house, you should
definitely take out a personal accident
policy.  If you
ask why, we
know that in our day and age, the roads we travel on,
accidents, and problems with various animals, from dogs to snakes, are all things
we
see in the news every day in our country.  Tomorrow we too may
become one of them.  If such a
situation arises, sometimes we might
survive the accident
.  But it's not necessarily possible to
go back to a healthy life
.  If such a situation arises,
we will receive a large amount of money in our
hands and with that amount
we will be able to
start a business and move forward with our
life.
Personal accident is a system that
covers all types of accidents, and we can
optionally add personal accident policies to it
.  I don't want to
take this anymore.  The personal
accident policy comes with a very small premium
.
Good personal
accident policies are available in the market if you can afford even Rs. 120 per month
.  So, if
you are someone who
travels frequently,
definitely take out a personal accident policy like that.  If you are over 18
years old and your
family is going to die because of you,
you should 100%
take out that policy.  It's
your choice whether or not to take out health insurance, but
you should
definitely take out a personal accident policy.
A friend of mine is a person who works
very seriously in the investment sector, working in mutual funds
.  One thing he once told me is that there is
a minimum criteria for investing
.  There are minimum criteria for us to get a loan
.  There are many things like civil service, income, etc.
Similarly,
there are minimum criteria for investing.   The very
first criterion is to
take out a personal accident policy so that we don't lose our investment if an accident happens to us
.  If we were to
start investing without taking out any insurance, it would be
like pouring water into a pot.  If you were to
start investing without taking out any insurance, it would be like
pouring water into a pot.  It will be poured on one side and then on the other
side, and it will
continue like this.   So,
take out insurance to cover the risks.  Insurance is
not an investment option.  Risk
coverage is an option.  You need to
approach insurance with that mindset.  So
we can add the PA policy here
.  Naturally, a 90-day
waiting period is applicable within this
.  Now, who can take out this policy? The
most important thing is that only those who do not have any
illnesses can
get this policy.  Most sum insured policies
require a medical test for this,
so if you don't have any
particular medical conditions,
take it immediately.  Now
let's see if it's a starting stage in a small way.
Let's apply and see how it goes
.  You can tell me.
So who can take out this policy?
This policy can be taken out by people between the ages of 18 and 65.  In other words,
any person who is 18 years of age or older and legally a citizen of India can
take out this policy. Those up to the age of 65 can
take it out.  Similarly,
we have a waiting period of 90
days, 120 days, and 150 days, depending on
the options available in this plan.
We also
have flexibility within this during the survival period.  As I
said earlier, you can take a zero-day survival period, or you can take
three days,
seven days, or 14 days if you want.
We can decide according to our preference, taking into account our premium.
Similarly, there is a policy tenure.
If you want, you can take it for one year or
two years at a time
.  You can take it together for a maximum of three years
.  Now, suppose a
person between the ages of 18 and 65 starts this policy,
he can continue for life. If
a criticality occurs, he can continue. If the
next criticality occurs, he can
continue again. If
any criticality in these five categories occurs,
he can claim five times.
On the other hand, if you take a plan that has coverage only for cancer, you
only
cover cancer there. With that,
its purpose will be complete. The
purpose we mentioned earlier is that we
take a criticality policy and if a criticality occurs,
then its
purpose will be complete. This is what
happens with most policies in the market.
Here, when we
take a comprehensive policy, we cover up to five criticalities.
Then we can do it in a way that one is repeated
and the next one is repeated.
So, we can say that we are sum assured and these five
types of sum assured are complete.
We can complete it until the day we can. If
we have
added the restoration benefit for cancer, if it is
cancer,
we can restore it as many times as we want and continue it
until our death.
This is
also a policy that provides benefits under 80DE to those who file our income tax.
Another important thing is that in this policy, as I
said earlier, medical tests are
mandatory in many categories. In some cases,
they are done according to our condition.
But the
company does not have to spend money from our hand for it. The company will
spend that money from their hand and
conduct the medical test. We
only need to go to the place they tell us for the medical test. Now, let
me tell you one more thing: who needs a medical test? For
those between the ages of 18 and 50, it is only if they
take a plan with an insured value of more than 25 lakhs. For
those between the ages of 51 and 55, the medical test comes with a
sum assured of more than 20 lakhs.  The
medical test is mandatory only if you take it. If you are
between 56 and 60, you will have to
take a medical test even if you take a sub-insurance of more than 10 lakhs
.  That is to say, if
they take a policy for a million rupees, they
won't have to take a medical test. If they
take ten or more, they will only be
given a policy after the medical.
Even if they say they don't have any health issues, they will only be given medical attention
.  Now, for those
above the age of 61 and up to the age of 65, a
medical test is mandatory regardless of the reason.  So, the
best choice is to take this as early as possible.  Now there
is another condition in this plan. The reason for this plan is that
they have put some conditions
in it. It is said that you can
choose the sum insured according to the age band.
Now, for those between the ages of 18 and 40, it is up
to 40 lakhs. If
we say that it is a comprehensive plan, it is five times that, that is, up to a crore. Didn't we say that it will
cover other critical conditions and you can choose a maximum of
40 lakhs for it? If you are
between the ages of 18 and 40,
then a 41-year-old can select up to 35 lakhs. For those between the ages of
41 and 45, you can choose 35 lakhs, for those between the ages of
46 and
50, you can choose 30 lakhs, for those between the ages of 51 and
55, you can choose 25 lakhs, and for
those between the ages of 56 and 60, you
can choose only 15 lakhs.
So we have a sum insured.
Whatever your age is, take as much as you
can afford, or wait a little longer. The
best
option is to choose one of these age groups as soon as possible. That's all
I have to tell you about this plan.
Now, we will end this video by mentioning one or two
important issues. The
first thing is how the
claim will work. Now, when
we say health insurance,
we naturally think that the
hospital bill will be settled.
But in this, the hospital bill is
not settled. If the amount
we are taking now is Rs. 10 lakh
or Rs. 40 lakh, if
we
can give the proof of it to the company when the criticality comes, the company will
evaluate it and accept it.
The company will give this amount to our bank account. There will be no tax on
this amount. This amount is not taxable. So, we will
get this amount in our account without tax. Now, let's
take an example of a very early stage of cancer.  If it
is found at this stage and it
is cancer, will we be given this 40 lakhs or
not, 25% of it will be
given first. If we have taken 10 lakhs, we will be given 2.5 lakhs
first. If
someone has taken 40 lakhs,
we will be given 10 lakhs first. We will be given 25%
later. If we have a critical illness,
this cancer itself is a
serious stage for us. Later, if
we are found, we will be given the remaining 75%. Or, if it is at the
critical stage right from the beginning, that is, if it is a major
illness, a major critical illness,
we will be given the entire amount in
one stretch to our
account. So, for
more details about this plan, if
you are planning to take this plan,
you can call me on my number that I have given in this video for that. You can
also watch other videos on my channel.
Let's learn about health insurance.
All I can say is that
whatever decision we make in the financial field, we should
do it only after we are convinced
.  It is never something we should jump into, subject to someone's
influence, coercion, or advice
.  It is
a decision we have to make based on our own convictions
.  If you are planning to
take such a plan, whether it is to take a health insurance
or a term
insurance, to
cover the risk that may occur in your life, you can
definitely contact me on my number. We should
always be able to
identify both risk and expense, or we should be able to
identify what loss and expense are. We
already know that it is an expense that we are going to incur. If we know that it is an
expense, we will never consider it as a loss.
We use electricity at home. When we
use electricity for lighting or other things that use electricity for an extra long
time,
we know that the bill will come.
That's an expense as far as we're concerned.
Because it's something we already know
.  At the same time,
we
can't predict when a lightning strike will strike a good TV.  Losing it is a
loss.  So, before we go ahead and
buy insurance for it, that's what
insurance does.
We can't buy it just to protect ourselves from the current bills. To
give another example, we
can't give coverage for the delivery of a pregnant woman who has conceived, because even if it is guaranteed, she will
deliver after nine months. Otherwise, an
abortion may occur in the meantime.
Meanwhile, we cannot be sure whether the child who is born will have
any illness or will have a
disability.
Therefore, you can take out a
policy that covers the child you are born with
.  This is what is
called the difference insurance difference.  So, make sure
you take all this.  I apologize for the video
being so long.
Until next time, I would like to
thank everyone with my heartfelt greetings and see you all with another great video
.  One more reminder: if you
like our channel videos, please
like the video.
Share those videos with others.  Subscribe to the channel
.  Your
subscription is my motivation.